# YOONHYUNG LEE

1, Gwanak-ro, Gwanak-gu, Seoul, Republic of Korea, 08826

<u>cpi1234@snu.ac.kr</u>·www.linkedin.com/in/yoonhyunglee· https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=N2p8CLkAAAAJ&hl=ko

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am a 4th-year Ph.D. candidate student in the Machine Intelligence Lab at the Seoul National University. My primary research interests lie in the area of Text-to-Speech and Spoken Language Modeling, and more specifically, aligning different modalities for multimodal deep learning model.

## **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. Candidate, Electrical and Computer Engineering, Seoul National University, 2019.03 – Present, Machine Intelligence Laboratory (Advisor: Kyomin Jung)

B.S., Electrical and Computer Engineering, Seoul National University, 2012.02-2019.

## **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

#### SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS, SEOUL, KOREA, JAN. 2018 ~ FEB. 2018

As an Internship program, I worked at advanced CP Lab in Samsung Electronics IT & Mobile Communications division.

#### NCSOFT SPEECH AI LAB, PANGYO, KOREA, JUL. 2021 ~ AUG. 2021

As an Internship program, I worked at Speech AI Lab in NCSOFT, and I researched about controlling expressiveness in Text-to-Speech.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- · Lee, Y., Yang, J., Jung, K. (2022) VarianceFlow: High-quality and Controllable Text-to-Speech Using Variance Information via Normalizing Flow (ICASSP) 2022.
- · Lee, Y., Shin, J., Jung, K. (2021) Bidirectional Variational Inference for Non-Autoregressive Text-to-Speech. International Conference on Learning Representation (ICLR) 2021.
- · Lee, Y., Yoon, S., Jung, K. (2020) Multimodal Speech Emotion Recognition Using Cross Attention with Aligned Audio and Text. Proc. Interspeech 2020, 2717-2721, DOI: 10.21437/Interspeech.2020-2312.
- · Shin, J., Lee, Y., Yoon, S., & Jung, K. (2020). Fast and Accurate Deep Bidirectional Language Representations for Unsupervised Learning. ACL.

- · Shin, J., Lee, Y. & Jung, K.. (2019). Effective Sentence Scoring Method Using BERT for Speech Recognition. Proceedings of The Eleventh Asian Conference on Machine Learning, in PMLR 101:1081-1093
- · Lee, Y., Kim, Y., & Jung, K. (2019). MILAB at SemEval-2019 Task 3: Multi-View Turn-by-Turn Model for Context-Aware Sentiment Analysis. SemEval@NAACL-HLT.
- ·주성호, 이윤형, 정교민 (2021). 멀티모달 가우시안 분포 기반 VAE 를 활용한 감정표현 음성 합성.한국정보과학회 학술발표논문집, 573-575 (우수논문상, Top 10% of the accepted papers)
- · 김성윤, 신중보, 이윤형, 정교민. (2020). 특징 벡터 다양화를 통한 cGANs 의 데이터 증강 개선 연구. 한국정보과학회 학술발표논문집, 1617-1619.

## **SCHOLARSHIPS**

YOULCHON AI STAR SCHOLARSHIPS, SEOUL, KOREA, JUL. 2022

Granted by Nongsim Youlchon Foundation

SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS, SEOUL, KOREA, JUL. 2018 ~ DEC. 2018

As a research scholarship student, I did a project to build an IoT chatbot using deep learning.

## **REVIEWER**

NeurIPS 2021 reviewer / ICLR 2022 reviewer

## **SKILLS**

- · Deep Learning Libraries: TensorFlow, Pytorch
- · Programming Languages: Python, C++, JAVA
- · Languages: Korean (Native), English (Intermediate)